## JAPHETH DIBO | INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY PROFESSIONAL **LOCATION: NAIROBI**

Telephone: +254742379085 Email: jeffreydibo@gmail.com

Accomplished IT professional with over 4 years background Technical Project management and support with a solid background in telephony and network engineering and enhancing system functionality. A solid track record of tackling and solving tough business and technical problems. Strong leader with demonstrated ability to work effectively with individuals at all levels and in all functional areas. I have amassed experience managing full project lifecycle from requirements gathering to final implementation and 1st and 2nd line technical support provision across public and private sector organizations.

## **Highlights of Expertise:**

• Project Management

Vendor Evaluation

Resource Management

• Innovative IT Initiatives

 Key Account Management Client Relations Strategy & Execution

Troubleshooting/Resolution

• End-user Support

#### **Technical Proficiencies:**

Platforms: Mac Os X, Windows 7/8/10/, Linux and MS Exchange 2012/2013/2016.

Hardware: HP, IBM, Dell Servers and Desktop Platforms, Cisco/Juniper/Huawei Switches, Sonic Wall

Hardware VPNs, HP Printers, Laptops, Physical APBX, VOIP Phone Systems.

Software: Cloud based PBX, MS Office, Power Bi (Business Analytics) Domains, Microsoft Dynamics (ERP,

CRM), and Cloud

Servers (Digital Ocean/AWS/Ali Baba) Emails Services (POP/IMAP) Virus-Prevention, Detection and

Removal.

Networking: TCP/IP/UDP, Wireless Technology (802.11 a/b/g), DNS, WINS, DHCP, Firewalls.

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

### ADVANCED DIPLOMA IN PROJECT MANAGEMENT

2019-To Date | Kenya Institute of Project Management

## **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY**

2011-2015 | JKUAT Grade: Second Class Honors (Lower Division).

## **MUSINGU BOYS HIGH SCHOOL**

2007-2010 | Grade: C+.

### ST. PETERS BOYS MUMIAS PRIMARY

1998-2006 | Grade: B+ (354 marks).

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## PROJECT MANAGER & IT LEAD AT WIN 365 LIMITED AUGUST 2018-To date My responsibilities are:

- ✓ Develop and deliver a project management program encompassing all the details of a project to the team members.
- ✓ Setting up the contact center which includes implementing the PABX infrastructure, IVR, SIP, CRM and training of contact center agents.
- ✓ Running regular checks on network and data security and identifying and acting on opportunities to improve and update software and systems
- ✓ Setting realistic and practical goals for the project and developing appropriate strategies for achieving these goals.
- ✓ Set up, maintain and repair workstations, printers, laptops, devices, software, and IT equipment hardware problems.
- ✓ Designing training programs and workshops for staff as well as conducting regular system audits.
- ✓ Identify all the internal and external resources whether financial or human resources required completing the project successfully.
- ✓ Evaluate the progress of project on regular basis and achieve set targets by detecting the problems that may arise in a timely manner.
- ✓ Developing and implementing IT policies and best practice guides for the organization.
- ✓ Assist in researching, procuring and set up of authorized IT equipment as well as keeping a detailed inventory of all IT equipment.
- ✓ Develop and execute an efficient internal communication strategy for ensuring communication with all levels of management within the team.
- ✓ Overseeing and determining timeframes for major IT projects including system updates, upgrades, migrations and outages.
- ✓ Set out the project boundaries and scope for the project which them formulates itself into a plan of action and assists in successful completion of the project.
- ✓ Managing risks which can have a negative impact on the project.
- ✓ Making sure all the necessary bills required are paid and documented on time to enable smooth business operation i.e. Domain Bills, Internet Bills, and other bills as required.

## SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR/TECHNICAL LEAD AT CARNATION PROPERTIES LIMITED MAY 2017 to AUGUST 2018

## My responsibilities included:

- ✓ Developing and implementing practices based on the standards of architecture.
- ✓ Assisting in the implementation of the computer systems and providing quality user support.
- ✓ Managing the network infrastructure and setting up user accounts and workstations.
- ✓ Troubleshooting errors, outages and upgrading systems with new releases and models.
- ✓ Analyze and evaluate network performance and provide solutions to optimize traffic flows, security, and processes.
- ✓ Website design, development and maintenance as well as website layouts/user interfaces by using standard HTML/CSS and JS practices.
- ✓ Working with product and design teams to understand the core problems and providing feedback.

- ✓ Maintenance and repair of ICT equipment and associated peripherals and reporting any faults for further action.
- ✓ Design, administer, maintain and support of the availability, performance and security of the network systems that include Routers, Firewalls, Switches, SBCs, PBX platforms, Circuits and servers evidencing strong knowledge of security, switching, and routing technologies.
- ✓ Implementing algorithms to integrate with existing and emerging systems or applications.
- ✓ Making sure all the IT systems are very secure and well maintained to avoid system penetration or malfunction.

# INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY OFFICER AT GAMCODE LIMITED SEPTEMBER 2016-APRIL 2017 My responsibilities included:

- ✓ Liaising with the IT manager to discuss and implement IS policies, standards, practices and security measures to ensure efficient, quality and consistent information processing operations and to safeguard information resources.
- ✓ Set up new franchise shops network and organize provision technical remote support for the shops this included installation of new hardware/software and maintaining them in case a malfunction occurs.
- ✓ Managing of IT hardware/software according to the corporate standards and regional guidelines, which included purchasing of IT equipment as per the company, polices, regulations and budget.
- ✓ Install required operating systems in new PCs and the relevant software's needed for day to day operations for example;-Back office software's, printer driver and other required software.
- ✓ Maintenance of the network, cameras, PCs in the office, shops and act as the intermediary between the company and the ISP by escalating to the appropriate party.
- ✓ Providing support to over 200 users on a daily basis on IT software/hardware, helpdesk service as well as fix any user devices like work stations, laptops, tablets, smartphones or printers.
- ✓ Installation of PowerEdge R230 Rack Server and Windows Server 2012 R2 this included operating system installation, configurations and racking.
- ✓ Preparing and updating documentations including but not limited to outage report of network service, network topology, system diagram and user support materials.
- ✓ Setting up, configuring and implementing call center equipment like the Server, PBX (Sangoma Vega 1000), E1 card and call center software that ran on Java client platform, web IP access platform and soft phone (eyebeam).
- ✓ Assisted in training of call center supervisors and agents on how the call center system works and runs as well as day-to-day technical support on various software and hardware issues experienced at the call center for example sound malfunction and software malfunction.
- ✓ Application of service level agreements to prioritize work accordingly like preparation of IT weekly schedule and training of the IT support team.
- ✓ Drive innovation, prioritizing IT initiatives, and coordinating the evaluation, deployment, and management of current and future IT systems by doing daily weekly and periodic checks to ensure all the hardware and software's are well-updated and operational at all times and the systems are working as required.
- ✓ Providing Level 2 support for technical infrastructure issues and maintain positive infrastructure applications service delivery trends, correct as needed as well as propose refined metrics to establish continuous improvement.

## ASSISTANT NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR AT MEDIA KALI AUGUST 2015-JUNE 2016 My main responsibilities were:-

- ✓ Diagnosing and fixing problems or potential problems with the network and its hardware, software and systems
- ✓ Troubleshooting network problems, administering network security and network services.
- ✓ Making sure the database is secure and well maintained.
- ✓ Timely preparation of customer orders, invoices and pro-active follow up on customer enquiries.
- ✓ Providing high level of customer service and negotiation skills for both walk-in and customer telephone queries this helped increase sales from 10% to 30% in just a month.
- ✓ Updating the website, maintain and set up the network on regular basis, repairing of printers and keeping daily records of orders and sales made.
- ✓ Maintaining the system and making sure it is fully functional to enable customer efficiency.

## INTERN AT KIBERA LAW COURTS MAY 2015-JULY 2015 My responsibilities included:-

- ✓ Trained staff on how to use Linux operating system, printers and how to connect to the internet alongside providing IT related support like software and hardware support.
- ✓ Data entry of court cases, bonds, bails and emailing of memorandums to the staff. Implementing court case allocation and filling system through which court cases would be assigned to various Magistrates via the system.
- ✓ Troubleshoot issues with the equipment's like printers, computers and servers.
- ✓ Making sure the UPS and air conditioner in the server room were fully functional at all times in case of power surges.
- ✓ Repairing and upgrading staff computers like installation of the operating systems, antiviruses and other software. I also learnt Windows Servers, Symantec Backup Exec extensively.
- ✓ Run software updates, installation and backup when requested.

### **REFEREES**

- Mrs. Carol Mwangi, Human Resource Manager, Gam Code Limited, 0722 242770. ca.mwangi@betin.co.ke
- Mrs. Ann Onginjo, Chief Magistrate, Kibera Law Courts
  P. O. Box 21039-00100, 0720886115, anneadwera@gmail.com
- Mr. Job Nyakoe Moenga, IT Officer, Windsor Golf Hotel, 0721641680. j.moenga@gmail.com
- 4. Fabian Owour Operations Manager WIN 365 Limited. 0721948852 fabian@win365.co.ke